DIGHELLE DILLOPER

GET IN TOUCH

Phone: (469) 583-6383 Email: rbillones921@gmail.com Linkedin: /in/richellebillones/ Github: github.com/rchlblns Website: rchlblns.github.io

PERSONAL BACKGROUND

Self motivated web developer with previous experience in data and healthcare industries. Skilled in both client and server side languages and frameworks. Keen interest in utilizing strengths in problem solving, communication, and customer service to enhance user experiences on the web

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Frontend

React, Javascript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize

Rackend

Node.js, Express, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, ORM, MongoDB

Design Tools

Photoshop, Illustrator

Other

Responsive design, Scrum and Agile methodologies, RESTful API design, Git, Command Line (Bash)

PROJECTS

Pacer TMS

HTML | CSS | Javascript | Node.js | Express.js | MySQL

- Designed frontend with Bootstrap and Handlebars
- Created and mapped database using MySQL and Sequelize
- Defined routing methods using Node.js and Express.js

Social Animals

React | MongoDB | Express.js | Node.js

- Designed frontend using Material Design for Bootstrap React version
- Integrated Google Custom Search API to provide users with pet related information and resources

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Texas ENT Specialists

Audiology Assistant | March 2016 to February 2020

- Supported audiologists in patient care and management by troubleshooting and resolving issues with device functioning and connectivity
- Enhanced patient satisfaction by addressing inquiries and concerns
- Managed department equipment, supplies, and stock to facilitate an optimal work environment

Raterlabs

Internet Analyst/Independent Contractor | September 2013 to April 2018

- Enhanced the efficiency of a popular search engine by providing comparative analysis of search results
- Synthesized data into valuable insights to improve user experience across multiple platforms
- Maintained a high level of data rating accuracy monthly

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

The University of Texas at Austin - Center for Professional Development Certificate, Full Stack Web Development | August 2018 - February 2019

University of North Texas

BS Speech Language Pathology and Audiology | August 2013 - December 2014

Baylor University

BA Psychology | August 2008 - May 2012